# **ROLAND JAY M. BRUCE**

House no. 254 Dayapan Ilaya, Lemery, Batangas, Philippines Mobile: +639171275487 | Whatsapp: +639063892745 |

Email: bruz.rj@gmail.com Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/roland-jay-bruce-55b895200

Portfolio: <a href="https://ribruce.netlify.app/">https://ribruce.netlify.app/</a>

## **SUMMARY**

A software engineer with proven track record in IT solutions sector. An extensive experience working with architects and experienced developers gave me the ability to be highly efficient in solving problems and identifying pain points from variety of angles. mainly exposed in backend development in microservices architecture but also into full stack development using variety of technologies and frameworks, providing solutions such as high-level and low-level design, technical research, and development.

## **SKILL SET**

#### LANGUAGES/TECHNOLOGIES

- Java 8 17 21
- **Typescript**
- SQL
- CSS
- HTML

#### **FRAMEWORKS**

- **Spring Framework**
- Spring boot
- **Spring Security**
- Spring Data JPA
- Spring Cloud
- Junit
- Cucumber
- Hibernate
- Swagger
- Kafka
- Talend ETL
- Angular (Typescript)
- React (Typescript)
- Drools/JBOSS Drools

## **DEVELOPMENT ENVIRONMENT**

- IntelliJ
- **Eclipse**
- Visual Studio Code
- Heidi SQL
- **SQL** Developer
- Talend Studio

#### CONTAINERIZATION

- **Kubernetes**
- Docker
- Helm

#### **CODE REPOSITORIES**

- Git
- **Bitbucket**
- GitLab
- Gerrit

#### SSH TOOLS

- MobaXterm
- Putty

#### **OPERATING SYSTEM**

- Windows
- MacOS
- Linux

#### SDLC

- Agile
- lira
- Confluence
- Azure DevOps
- Waterfall
- Scrum
- SAFe

#### **BUILD/AUTOMATION TOOLS**

- Azure DevOps
- Maven
- Gradle
- **Jenkins**

#### **TESTING TOOLS**

- Postman
- SoapUI
- Advance Rest Client

#### DATABASE/STORAGE

- MySQL
- Oracle
- MariaDB
- **PostgreSQL**
- MongoDB
- Nexus

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## ING HUBS PHILIPPINES - (APRIL 1. 2024 - PRESENT) AS A SENIOR BACKEND ENGINEER

#### **Roles:**

- Refine, develop, and test BAU and improvement features/stories.
- Aid team's blockers and concerns regarding daily tasks.
- Created a global template and ansible roles to Deploy spring boot application with secure policies.
- Delivered a complex change involving the alignment of a large set of customer data, which was a crucial step in standardization, data quality improvements, and reduction of duplicate records. This resolved more than 4 million data quality issues in a single country.
- Serving as ING Blue Security Champion, responsible for conducting secure code reviews and analyzing Checkmarx scan results for my team and supporting other team across the Area/Tribe to uphold security standards and best practices.





## ATOS SYNTEL INFOTECH, INC. (MARCH 2023 - MARCH 2024) AS A JAVA FULLSTACK DEVELOPER (GCM4)



- Roles:
- Developing multiple features with cross-team collaboration and maintenance of multiple microservices with competing priorities.
- Test, maintain, and recommend software improvements to ensure strong functionality and optimization
- Developing new Drools rules for a country specific requirement.
- Ensures code quality and understandable feature by creating component test and generating test reports using Cucumber.
- Supporting Architects on reviewing code changes, and make sure all the relevant verification has been completed such as UT coverage, Sonar analysis, local testing and build success.

#### **Career milestones:**

#### **China Data localization**

Worked on application migration to support China Data localization which includes infrastructure setup, data migration, app remediation and quality testing. Provided an architectural solution to solve migration strategy such as unavailability of some technologies in China and focused on application remediation of existing backend and frontend application built using **Spring boot and Angular 15**, which includes externalizing static link and properties used on existing country, updating automation tests using **cucumber** for backend and **Cypress** for fronted.

Initiated use of Docker over PCF which is not supported in China Colo. Created the base images for all other app image and provided a plan for image orchestration. **Docker and Kubernetes.** 

#### Added Support for import/export functionalities in custom Clearance process.

Developed an application for logistic company that carries out the customs clearance process which uses asynchronous messaging service to integrate with 3<sup>rd</sup> party applications to meet its delivery commitments to customers – **JMS queue**, **Apache Kafka**, and creation of **JMS to Kafka bridge** and **Kafka to JMS bridge**.

### WIPRO (AUGUST 2022 - MARCH 2023) AS A PROJECT ENGINEER

#### **Roles:**



- Mainly focuses on Microservices development, for A leading Telecom company in Australia for their ordering system and service management.
- Collaborate with the designer to generate estimates for each user story.
- Perform code reviews of Junior's output before code check in, ensure technical solutions and implementation meets the functionality with minimum code complexity.
- Work with a powerful technology stack, Spring, Kafka, Elastic Search, Consul, Angular, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, docker, Kubernetes.
- Supporting SIT by providing reliable root cause reports and applying bug fixes.
- Develop ground up microservice acting as a rule engine for all other microservice. Spring boot, Drools, Kafka

## ACCENTURE INC. (JUNE 2021 - AUGUST 2022) AS A SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER



#### **Career milestone:**

#### Client Account Recognition (A leading Biotechnology Center in Europe) - Leadership winner

Developed Test Case generator to test data imported in the tool. Implemented Abstract factory to produce different types of test cases without specifying their concrete types during creation. Recognition remarks: guided other resources on how they can proceed whenever they encounter blockers related to their task; by owning and fixing issues that were reported by the testing team during validation; and by sending timely overall progress reports of the team. Spring boot, Rest API, Feign Client, Microservices, Message stream, RabbitMQ, MongoDB

#### Created and integrated a microservice compare tool in the project

Compare tool show the additional data, changes, and deletions in the project by comparing generated xml of different projects or at different stages of the current project: **Angular, Spring boot, Rest API, web sockets.** 

### **Roles:**

- Design, maintain and develop enterprise application solution and software based on requirements.
- Integrates test, and debug solution deployed in multiple environments.
- Involve in requirement analysis and estimation, measures effort with respect to the time it will take to complete a task.
- Enforces compliance on code coverage and code improvements by utilizing code analysis tools Sonarqube.
- Manages software releases of the team, responsible on compiling each release images before sending to the stakeholders.
- Provides technical assistance and consultations to software engineer members and testing team.

Pull docker images and upload on client UAT and Beta Version environment using Rancher, switching branches Prod, Dev and Beta version.

### EY GDS PHILIPPINES (FEBRUARY 2021 – JUNE 2021) AS AN IAM JAVA DEVELOPER



#### **Roles:**

- Java Developer for SailPoint, Creating custom scripts for Business process, bundle, etc: Java Core, Java EE, SailPoint
- Perform development activities using a variety of computer programming languages such as SQL, HTML5, JavaScript (JS) and Java Enterprise Development to develop, modify, and manage code aligned business rules.

## GREEN ADVANCEDTECH SOLUTION CORP (AUGUST 2019 – JANUARY 2021) AS A SYSTEM DEVELOPER

### **GREEN ADVANCEDTECH SOLUTION CORP.**

#### **Roles:**

- Involved in analysis and development of delivery personnel tracking web and mobile application.
- Involved in planning, design, analysis, and backend development of HR management System for GRS in JAPAN: Java, Spring boot, Angular, web and mobile responsive app
- Involved in code refactoring and maintenance of GASC Attendance and Employee Management System: Java, Spring, Web MVC, JSP, web and mobile responsive app
- Facilitates application exams and interviews for aspiring applicants.
- Work closely with the company Japanese counterpart to effectively resolve issues.

#### PROFESSIONAL RECOGNITION AND CERTIFICATIONS

**Azure Fundamentals AZ-900** 

Remarks: Transcript ID: 1333372; Access Code: AZ900xBruce

### Accenture Inc. FY22 Application Modernization and Optimization Gantimpala Award

Remarks: Agila (Execute with agility)

Be at ease with ambiguity and uncertainty Productivity and Quality champion

**Best Developer** 

#### Client and Accenture Inc. Excellence in Collaboration Recognitions

Remarks: Leadership, recognized for: His contributions, helped the team delivered on time: by guiding them. by fixing issues reported; and by sending team overall progress report.

## **EDUCATION**

REFERENCES

LYCEUM OF THE PHILIPPINES UNIVERSITY - BATANGAS

**Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering** 

2019 Graduate

\*\*\*Available upon request\*\*\*